PROFESSOR: Today we're going to talk
about how to do search in the presence
of uncertainty.
In particular, we're going to think
about how you should plan when the
outcome of your actions is not
entirely under your control.
We've actually already seen
an example of this.
If you think about an adversarial
context, you can think about that as a
case where you take an action.
You make your move.
And the outcome of that action,
you can think of that as
your opponent's response.
And your opponent isn't entirely
under your control.
And we thought about last time was how
to reason when your opponent's
response could be assumed
to be adversarial.
And we thought about minimax
trees and minimax values.
So for example, in a tree like this,
we would say, well, let's imagine
we're playing against
a perfect adversary.
A perfect adversary would say, if
I make the left move, then I can
actually predict what the
adversary will do.
If I make the right move, again, I can
predict what the adversary will do.
And the adversary will choose 9, even
though I would really like that 100.
The adversary is just not
going to let it happen.
And that 100 doesn't contribute to the
minimax value of the right node.
That is the correct reasoning when
you're facing an adversary.
Or at least when you're facing
a perfect adversary.
What happens when you're
facing this guy?
This guy may be generally trying to
win, but maybe he's not perfect.
Maybe he makes mistakes.
Sometimes he makes the wrong move.
Well now maybe making that right action
is kind of appealing, because
you've got a decent shot at the
100, and the 9 is not so bad.
Or even more, what if the response
to your action--
the outcome--
isn't adversarial at all, it's just
the result of rolling some die?
In this case, we should still think
about our actions having unknown
results, but rather than thinking that
the results are worst case, we should
be thinking about some
kind of average case.
And we should be thinking that those
aren't really min nodes, but they're
some kind of chance node.
And the general idea for today is going
to be to think about the case
where all uncertainty is controlled by
chance, and not by an adversary.